{
	"cards": [
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-1",
			"front": "Premature separation of the placenta from the wall of the uterus.",
			"back": "abruptio placentae"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-2",
			"front": "The fluid-filled, baglike membrane in which the fetus develops.",
			"back": "amniotic sac"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-3",
			"front": "Describes a condition in which the patient has too few red blood cells, resulting in a decreased ability to transport oxygen throughout the body via the bloodstream.",
			"back": "anemic"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-4",
			"front": "A scoring system for assessing the status of a newborn that assigns a number value to each of five areas.",
			"back": "Apgar score"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-5",
			"front": "The vagina and cervix.",
			"back": "birth canal"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-6",
			"front": "A small amount of blood in the vagina that appears at the beginning of labor and may include a plug of pink-tinged mucus that is discharged when the cervix begins to dilate.",
			"back": "bloody show"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-7",
			"front": "A delivery in which the buttocks come out first.",
			"back": "breech presentation"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-8",
			"front": "The lower third, or neck, of the uterus.",
			"back": "cervix"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-9",
			"front": "The appearance of the fetus’s head at the vaginal opening during labor.",
			"back": "crowning"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-10",
			"front": "A pregnancy complication that is characterized by new-onset hypertension (systolic blood pressure  greater than 140 mm Hg or diastolic blood pressure  greater than 90 mm Hg) with seizure activity and preceding systemic effects, such as blurred vision, headache, or protein in the urine. It is differentiated from preeclampsia by the presence of seizure activity.",
			"back": "eclampsia"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-11",
			"front": "A pregnancy that develops outside the uterus, typically in a fallopian tube.",
			"back": "ectopic pregnancy"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-12",
			"front": "The early stage of development after the fertilization of the egg (first 10 weeks).",
			"back": "embryo"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-13",
			"front": "The lining of the inside of the uterus.",
			"back": "endometrium"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-14",
			"front": "A condition caused by the consumption of alcohol by a pregnant woman; characterized by growth and physical problems, mental retardation, and a variety of congenital abnormalities in her child.",
			"back": "fetal alcohol syndrome"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-15",
			"front": "The developing, unborn infant inside the uterus, from 10 weeks after fertilization until birth.",
			"back": "fetus"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-16",
			"front": "The dome-shaped top of the uterus.",
			"back": "fundus"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-17",
			"front": "Diabetes that develops during pregnancy in women who did not have diabetes before pregnancy.",
			"back": "gestational diabetes"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-18",
			"front": "A blood pressure greater than or equal to 140 mm Hg systolic or 90 mm Hg diastolic in a pregnant female in whom hypertension has not previously been diagnosed.",
			"back": "gestational hypertension"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-19",
			"front": "The elective termination of a pregnancy prior to the time of viability.",
			"back": "induced abortion"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-20",
			"front": "The movement of the fetus down into the pelvis late in pregnancy.",
			"back": "lightening"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-21",
			"front": "A delivery in which the presenting part is a single arm or leg.",
			"back": "limb presentation"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-22",
			"front": "Fetal stool. When appearing as a dark green material in the amniotic fluid, it can indicate distress or disease in the newborn; it can be aspirated into the fetus’s lungs during delivery.",
			"back": "meconium"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-23",
			"front": "The first menstrual cycle or onset of the first menstrual bleeding in females.",
			"back": "menarche"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-24",
			"front": "The cessation of menstruation, typically in the fourth or fifth decade of life.",
			"back": "menopause"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-25",
			"front": "The spontaneous passage of the fetus and placenta before 20 weeks; also called spontaneous abortion.",
			"back": "miscarriage"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-26",
			"front": "A woman who has had previous pregnancies.",
			"back": "multigravida"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-27",
			"front": "An umbilical cord that is wrapped around the fetus’s neck.",
			"back": "nuchal cord"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-28",
			"front": "The area of the skin between the vagina and the anus.",
			"back": "perineum"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-29",
			"front": "The tissue attached to the uterine wall that nourishes the fetus through the umbilical cord.",
			"back": "placenta"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-30",
			"front": "A condition in which the placenta develops over and covers the cervix.",
			"back": "placenta previa"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-31",
			"front": "A pregnancy complication that is characterized by new-onset hypertension (systolic blood pressure  greater than 140 mm Hg or diastolic blood pressure  greater than 90 mm Hg) along with systemic effects, such as blurred vision, headache, or protein in the urine. Differentiated from eclampsia by the lack of seizure activity.",
			"back": "preeclampsia"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-32",
			"front": "The position in which an infant is born; defined by the part of the body that appears first.",
			"back": "presentation"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-33",
			"front": "A woman who is experiencing her first pregnancy.",
			"back": "primigravida"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-34",
			"front": "A situation in which the umbilical cord comes out of the vagina before the fetus.",
			"back": "prolapse of the umbilical cord"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-35",
			"front": "A development defect in which a portion of the spinal cord or meninges may protrude outside of the vertebrae and possibly even outside of the body, usually at the lower third of the spine in the lumbar area.",
			"back": "spina bifida"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-36",
			"front": "The loss of a pregnancy prior to 20 weeks of gestation without any preceding surgical or medical intervention. Often called a miscarriage.",
			"back": "spontaneous abortion"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-37",
			"front": "Low blood pressure resulting from compression of the inferior vena cava by the weight of the pregnant uterus when the woman is supine.",
			"back": "supine hypotensive syndrome"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-38",
			"front": "The structure that connects the pregnant woman to the fetus via the placenta; contains two arteries and one vein.",
			"back": "umbilical cord"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-39",
			"front": "A white, cheesy substance that covers the body of the fetus.",
			"back": "vernix caseosa"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-vocabulary-card-40",
			"front": "A delivery in which the head of the newborn comes out first.",
			"back": "vertex presentation"
		}
	],
	"category": {
		"value": "chapter-34",
		"label": "Chapter 34"
	},
	"tags": [
		{
			"value": "vocabulary",
			"label": "Vocabulary"
		}
	]
}